<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Module>
<ModulePrefs 
title="Today In Computing History" 
height="260" 
width="240"
author="Robert Watkins" 
author_email="robert@watkins.net" 
description="Today In Computing History" 
thumbnail="http://img.uptodown.net/icons/erase-temp.png"
screenshot="http://img.uptodown.net/icons/erase-temp.png"/>
<Content type="html"><![CDATA[
<script type="text/javascript">
var Events = new Array();
Events[0]=["January","1","1983","ARPANET starts to talk like the Internet","The ARPANET will become the internet, but on this day, it begins to use TCP/IP (aka the Internet Protocol). Effectively preparing the fifteen year old network to communicate like the Internet does to this day.","Saturday"];
Events[1]=["January","2","1920","Isaac Asimov is born","This author coined the '3 laws of Robotics' -<1>- A robot may not injure, or allow to be injured, any human being  -<2>- A robot must obey any orders given to it by human beings, except if it conflicts with the First Law. -<3>- A robot must protect its own existence except if it conflicts with the First or Second Law.","Sunday"];
Events[2]=["January","3","1977","Apple Computer is incorporated","The founders, Steve Jobs, Steve Wozniack and Ronald Wayne founded Apple Computer the year before. On this day they formalized the corporation that has gone on to set high expectations of design and usability in not just the personal computer market, but also to other personal technology.","Monday"];
Events[3]=["January","4","1962","The first 'unmanned' subway is introduced in New York City","This was the beginning of a six month trial that would have started the month before except the subway drivers threatened to strike. The strike was avoided by having a driver on board during the trial runs.","Tuesday"];
Events[4]=["January","5","1972","President Nixon announces NASA's plans for the Space Shuttle","Richard Nixon announces in a statement that in order to allow our scientists to continue to do the important work in space, a new Space Shuttle program is going to be started. This program will feature a re-usable craft that can greatly reduce the costs of new flights and minimize the necessary training needed to be aboard the craft.","Wednesday"];
Events[5]=["January","6","1995","Microsoft Bob is announced","Microsoft Bob was intended to be a user-friendly interface for using the computer. It was a massive failure with the public. At one point, the project was being directly managed by Melinda French, Bill Gate's girlfriend, and now wife. At the time the project was released, Ms. French was in charge of several products that included the ill-fated Bob.","Thursday"];
Events[6]=["January","7","1992","AT&T releases a 'video telephone'","While there were booths that could transmit video as early as 1964, this is AT&T's first consumer model. While MCI had one for sale about the same time, it was half of the $1499.00 that AT&T was asking.","Friday"];
Events[7]=["January","8","1991","Apple chairman John Scully coins the term 'Personal Digital Assistant'","At the Winter Consumer Electronic Show, Sculley describes a 'Personal Digital Assistant' as  a handheld computer that uses a stylus for input on an LCD screen. Further, he announces that Apple will enter the PDA market by the end of the year, signaling the coming of the Apple Newton.","Saturday"];
Events[8]=["January","9","2007","The Apple iPhone is announced","At the MacWorld Expo, Steve Jobs announced the iPhone, an internet-enabled phone, building on the previous success of the iPod.","Sunday"];
Events[9]=["January","10","1927","The movie 'Metropolis' is released in Germany","This silent movie stunned all audiences that saw it. The special effects and cityscapes showed a great deal of artistic and technical knowledge and ability. Additionally, this is one of the earliest appearances of a robot in movies, though the term robot was coined at least six years earlier.","Monday"];
Events[10]=["January","11","1934","C.A.R. Hoare is born","Hoare was one of the early scientists that put the 'science' in Computer Science. His work included studying the logic of computer programs including 'Hoare Logic' used to prove program correctness. He also created 'Quicksort' in 1960.","Tuesday"];
Events[11]=["January","12","1937","A plow for laying submarine cable is patented","As early as 1858, there were transatlantic cables used for telegraph lines, by 1940, there were transatlantic phone lines. Eventually, these lines would carry data and be supplemented by not only other types of wired connections, but wireless technologies as well.","Wednesday"];
Events[12]=["January","13","1874","A patent for the Spalding Adding Machine is issued","Mechanical adders such as this were used heavily until electro-mechanical versions were briefly used and ultimately replaced by computers starting in the 1960s.","Thursday"];
Events[13]=["January","14","1978","Kurt Godel Dies","Probably his most famous contribution to logic was regarding the trade-off between completeness and consistency. In essence it says, If the system was to be consistent, it was necessarily incomplete, meaning that some of it's axioms cannot be proven within itself and must be assumed to be true.","Friday"];
Events[14]=["January","15","1968","First US patent application filed for a video game","The system was simply called 'Brown Box' as that was exactly what it looked like. Within five years, the rights will be purchased and the Magnavox Odyssey would be the product.","Saturday"];
Events[15]=["January","16","1997","Clippy is born","While the first Microsoft Office suite was shipped some seven years earlier, Office 97 included such favorites as Grammar Checker and Clippy, the Office Assistant.","Sunday"];
Events[16]=["January","17","1969","IBM is charged with being a monopoly","The US Attorney General, Ramsey Clark, brings IBM up on charges of being a monopoly in the computer industry and seeks to break up the company. IBM successfully fights these charges and the government drops their case some thirteen years later.","Monday"];
Events[17]=["January","18","1995","yahoo.com was registered","Two years earlier, Stanford PhD students, David Filo and Jerry Yang,  track their favorite sites found on the internet. Over time, they spend more and more time on this project as more and more people found it useful. They eventually thought that a business could be made from this and they started Yahoo!","Tuesday"];
Events[18]=["January","19","1986","The first PC virus is reported","This virus, called The Brain, infected the boot sector of 360 kb disks, common at the time.","Wednesday"];
Events[19]=["January","20","1970","The 'Super Fight' film was released","This was the result of a settlement between Muhammed Ali and the producers of a 1968 series of radio broadcasts of computer-generated scripts of boxing matches where Ali 'lost' to Jim Jeffries, who died fifteen years earlier. The film consisted of re-assembled clips of Ali and the winner of the 1968 series, Rocky Marciano, sparing.","Thursday"];
Events[20]=["January","21","1888","Babbage's mechanical Analytical Engine passes  an initial test of it's design","Nearly a half-century before electronic computers are built, Charles Babbage designed a somewhat programmable mechanical computer. On this day, a portion of that design was constructed and shown to work as expected. In 2009 a working version of the full design was completed.","Friday"];
Events[21]=["January","22","1984","The Apple Mac is introduced","During the Super Bowl, the ad showing a lone woman standing up to an opressor by throwing a hammer at what appears to be a large television is shown. ","Saturday"];
Events[22]=["January","23","1996","The Java 1.0 development kit is released","Sun Microsystems envisioned a programming language that would not suffer from incompatibilities when the programs were moved to different platforms. The motto 'Write once, run anywhere' was a desirable trait for software that could run on Windows, Unix, Linux, MacOS and other lesser-known platforms. ","Sunday"];
Events[23]=["January","24","1980","Usenet is born","This is the first 'chat' system. Instead of private chat between two people, it takes more of a 'party line' approach, where anyone can post and read messages. The system only had a couple messages a day in 1980, by 2010, the daily volume reached over 5400 Gb (or 5,400,000 Mb) of traffic a day!","Monday"];
Events[24]=["January","25","1979","First death caused by a robot","Robert Williams is hit by a robotic arm in a plant in Flat Rock Michigan. Not much more is known about the incident. However, a few years later, a robotic arm pushed someone else into a grinding machine for a more gruesome death.","Tuesday"];
Events[25]=["January","26","1983","Lotus 1-2-3 is introduced","While not the first spreadsheet program, it was the first popular spreadsheet program. Many businesses used it to track data typically done by hand.","Wednesday"];
Events[26]=["January","27","1994","Jim Clark starts up a company that will become Netscape","Mosaic was one of the first widely-used web browsers. Originally developed by the NCSA and SGI, it was quickly commercialized. Mosaic Communications became Netscape. Eventually, Netscape was bought by AOL.","Thursday"];
Events[27]=["January","28","1952","Bank of America signs a contract to automate their check processing","The contract was with SRI following a previous feasibility study that concluded a system was possible. This first contract was only for a handful of branches. In 1959, the first 'production' version was installed and by 1966, nearly 900 branches were using this system, processing about 750 million checks a year.","Friday"];
Events[28]=["January","29","1988","Tetris is released in the US for PCs and the Commodore 64","The UK firm, Andromeda, and it's US subsidiary, Spectrum Holobyte, have released the software, even though they won't actually own the rights until May of the same year. Many companies ultimately get involved in producing versions, Tengen, Mirrorvision, Atari, Nintendo and more. The lawsuits are ultimately settled by 1993.","Saturday"];
Events[29]=["January","30","1925","The father of 'The Mother of All Demos' is born","Douglas Englebart gave this demo in 1968 where he introduced the computer mouse to the public for the first time, showed how his team mixed videoconferencing and desktop collaboration together, rudimentary computer graphics and much more. ","Sunday"];
Events[30]=["January","31","1995","AT&T announces plans to secure cellphone conversations","AT&T contract with VLSI to develop strategies for securing cell phone communications by installing security chips inside phones.","Monday"];
Events[31]=["February","1","1975","Microsoft gets it's first customer","Bill Gates and Paul Allen sell their newly-completed Altair BASIC to MITS. At this point, Microsoft is based in Albuquerque New Mexico with their first client and this version of BASIC is the first programming language available for a personal computer.","Tuesday"];
Events[32]=["February","2","2008","Microsoft attempts a hostile takeover of Yahoo!","In an attempt to start with an established product and other intellectual properties related to online advertising, Microsoft offers to buy Yahoo! shares at a premium over the current value. Eventually, Yahoo! successfully fought off this takeover.","Wednesday"];
Events[33]=["February","3","1976","Bill Gates accuses many computer enthusiasts of piracy","Being a programmer, Bill Gates was concerned that the work that goes into writing and producing a software program wasn't being honored when commercial software was copied and passed around. In an open letter to those that share commercial software with others, he accused them of piracy.","Thursday"];
Events[34]=["February","4","2004","Facebook is born","A student at Harvard, Mark Zuckerberg opened a social networking site to just fellow students. But that limitation was soon expanded to other Ivy League schools and ultimately to anyone.","Friday"];
Events[35]=["February","5","1996","Netscape 2.0 is released","While it may seem odd now, it wasn't free. It was sold for $49. It was available for Windows 3.1, Windows 95, Windows NT and Mac OS. ","Saturday"];
Events[36]=["February","6","1998","The v.90 modem standard is finalized","Arguably the last major version of modem standards for connecting to the internet (or other networks) by phone line. Modem usage has declined in favor of DSL, Cable and even cellphone-based 3G, 3.5G, 4G connectivity.","Sunday"];
Events[37]=["February","7","1997","Microsoft Announces that they will no longer support PowerPC for Windows NT","The Motorola PowerPC processor was used by Mac computers, but (ironically) there wasn't much demand for a PC based on a PowerPC processor.","Monday"];
Events[38]=["February","8","1999","Free-PC announces Free computers","The business model for this was to 'give away' computers with internet access to consumers in exchange for the users being shown advertisements. While many will be given away, there weren't enough companies paying for advertising to sustain this model and most companies were gone within a year of starting.","Tuesday"];
Events[39]=["February","9","1994","Electronic Arts and Broderbund Software, propose a merger ","Electronic Arts was mainly known for games and Broderbund did mostly a mix of utility and education software. This merger never completed. Had this merger completed, the new company would have been one of the largest producers of consumer software at the time.","Wednesday"];
Events[40]=["February","10","1998","The XML standard is proposed","XML is based on SGML, which was proposed ten years earlier. SGML didn't get much support due to it's complexity and lack of industry support. Common uses are to replace the original HTML markup with XHTML and to represent complex data in a cross-platform way for transmission between systems.","Thursday"];
Events[41]=["February","11","1966","RAND takes JOSS out of service","JOSS was only three years old at the time, but it had reached full capacity and needed to be replaced with a more powerful system that was capable of supporting more users.","Friday"];
Events[42]=["February","12","1977","The Boston Computer Society is founded","Jonathan Rotenberg conducts the first meeting of only four attendees. It eventually became one of the largest such user groups in the world and eventually disbanded in 1996.","Saturday"];
Events[43]=["February","13","1980","Apollo Computer is incorporated","Apollo Computer was an early producer of 'graphical computers'. These systems were useful in electronic and mechanical design work at a time when this ability was usually associated with much more expensive systems. They were ultimately bought by Hewlett-Packard in 1989.","Sunday"];
Events[44]=["February","14","1946","The ENIAC is shown for the first time in public","While a US patent was filed for the ENIAC it was revoked in 1974 after the makers of the Atanasoff-Berry Computer (from 1939) won a court battle that claimed that their computer was the first and the ENIAC had no valid claim on an 'electronic computer'.","Monday"];
Events[45]=["February","15","1995","Kevin Mitnick is arrested","Before this arrest, he had been involved in activities such as phone 'phreaking' and falsifying bus passes as early as the age of 12. This particular arrest was for a string of computer hacking activities as well as breaking the terms of an earlier parole. Today, he runs his own computer security company.","Tuesday"];
Events[46]=["February","16","1978","The BBS is born","These Bulletin Board Systems were discussion forums that were initially only available regionally due to the requirement of connecting to them by phone line. This type of discussion was not new for computers connected at universities, but it was new to the general public. This is one of the early forms of 'social networks'.","Wednesday"];
Events[47]=["February","17","1874","Thomas J. Watson Sr. is born","Thomas Watson Sr worked up from a salesman to lead the massive IBM corporation. During his time, he grew the company to be known world-wide for the punched-card equipment typical until the 1960s. He died in 1956 and his son, Thomas Watson Jr. was the one that brought IBM into the computer age.","Thursday"];
Events[48]=["February ","18","1745","Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta is born","While there is evidence of battery-type devices that go back much earlier, this is where the scientific study of battery technology starts.","Friday"];
Events[49]=["February","19","1949","Danielle Bunten Berry is born","This American-born game designer is known for her 1983 release of M.U.L.E., one of the first successful multi-player games. She also produced The Seven Cities of Gold a year later.","Saturday"];
Events[50]=["February","20","1947","Alan Turing suggests using Chess to test Artificial Intelligence","In a speech to the London Mathematical Society, he argues that using the game of Chess as a subject to teach an Artificial Intelligence system to learn the best ways to set up such AI systems. He argued that in much the same way that a human must be taught to become proficient, a computer can be taught.","Sunday"];
Events[51]=["February","21","1984","Timex exits the home computer market","Timex computers were low-powered, low-priced computers that provided accessibility to those unable to afford the larger computers. On this day, they decide that the market is starting to determine the winners and losers, and the winners won't include them.","Monday"];
Events[52]=["February","22","2010","The Dalai Lama creates a Twitter account","Known for his desire to keep up with current trends and academic thought, the real Dalai Lama creates a twitter account. Previous attempts for others to create an account on his behalf had been scuttled.","Tuesday"];
Events[53]=["February","23","1947","ISO is formed","The International Standards Organization provides a clearinghouse for many standards, including technical standards. There is no requirement that they be honored, but they are recognized as being an excellent source for ensuring consistency in technical products.","Wednesday"];
Events[54]=["February","24","1955","Steve Jobs is born","Steve Jobs is passionate about technology and has pushed the envelope in design and marketing. He's best known for co-founding Apple Computer, but he also started Pixar Studios and the NeXT Computer companies as well.","Thursday"];
Events[55]=["February","25","2003","Google's first patent is granted","US patent 6,526,440 grants Google rights to 'rank search results by reranking the results based on local inter-connectivity'. This is one of the pieces of the magic formula that they use to help find stuff on the internet. Since then, Google has become known for other products and services, Gmail, Google Maps, Google Docs and many more.","Friday"];
Events[56]=["February","26","1996","SGI buys Cray Research","This purchase was worth $767 million dollars and made Silicon Graphics Inc. the leading supplier of high-speed computing in the world. Cray Research was formed by Seymour Cray and many believe that he is the 'father of supercomputing'. He started Cray Research in the early 1970s after an already long career in other research labs.","Saturday"];
Events[57]=["February","27","1998","Development ceases for the Apple Newton","After Apple created the term PDA and filled this new niche with the Newton, it still had it's problems. So much so,  a Newton-like device showed up in a Simpson's episode where Nelson is making his to-do list where 'Beat up Martin' became 'Eat up Martha'. There are still enthusiasts that continue to use these products.","Sunday"];
Events[58]=["February","28","1956","Patent for Core Memory is granted","An Wang is granted his patent for a key component of Core Memory. Core memory consists of two rows of wires that form a checkerboard pattern with a magnetic ring (aka core),  around each set of crossed wires. Early on, it was not efficient to have this done by machine, so textile workers were hired to do this work by hand.","Monday"];
Events[59]=["March","1","1960","LISP 1 Programmer Manual is released","The LISP programming language stands for LISt Processing. Its original design was to be a formal language for describing programs and was quickly found to be useful for those studying Artificial Intelligence. The language was invented in 1958 and is still used today for AI research.","Tuesday"];
Events[60]=["March","2","1987","The Macintosh SE is introduced","Probably the most important feature of this system was it's expandability for additional memory and even a processor card. You could not only get 1 or 2 floppy drives, but also a hard drive (a first for the Macintosh line). A fan was added, which helped maintain a cooler temperature and therefore, a longer working life.","Wednesday"];
Events[61]=["March","3","2003","SCO announces it will sue IBM over Linux","2003 saw SCO sue many companies in an attempt to show that Linux had Unix code in it and that they should be compensated for that violation. As of 2010, there are still some lingering lawsuits being tried in court, with typically with SCO not being able to make their case.","Thursday"];
Events[62]=["March","4","1956","An Wang sells Core Memory Patent","Only days earlier, his patent that made Magnetic Core Memory possible was granted. IBM buys An Wang's patent for use in it's own systems. Wang Laboratories competes with IBM for many years but ultimately declares bankruptcy, gets bought and resold several times.","Friday"];
Events[63]=["March","5","1975","First meeting of the Homebrew Computer Club","Having a meeting in your garage with friends may not be an auspicious start to much, but for Gordon French, it was. Among the first attendees at this meeting in Menlo Park was Steve Wozniack. The name isn't proposed until a future meeting. ","Saturday"];
Events[64]=["March","6","2003","SCO makes good on threat of lawsuit","In Utah, SCO files a lawsuit against IBM. The claim is that IBM took Unix code (licensed from SCO) and added it to the Linux codebase. In order to speed a resolution, they further threaten to revoke the license agreement in 100 days if IBM does not meet their demands.","Sunday"];
Events[65]=["March","7","1997","w3c.org is registered","The World Wide Web Consortium (w3c) registers their own domain on this day, nearly one and a half years after Tim Berners-Lee founded the organization.","Monday"];
Events[66]=["March","8","1900","Howard Aiken's Birthday","Howard Aiken was the primary designer for the Mark I computer, completed in 1944.  While studying Physics,  he came across calculations that required enormous effort. This got him to think about building an electro-mechanical computer. With help from IBM and the US Military he was able to build this computer.","Tuesday"];
Events[67]=["March","9","1993","The PowerOpen Association was formed","This association of Apple, Motorola, IBM and four other companies was intended to promote new computer chip technology. The PowerPC platform released by Apple was one result of this effort.","Wednesday"];
Events[68]=["March","10","1997","Netscape Communicator Announced","While not released for several more months, this suite of software packages included a web browser, email client, news client, address book, HTML editor, Netcaster (a push client), Conference  (a multi-user communication application) and a calendar application. ","Thursday"];
Events[69]=["March","11","1890","Vannevar Bush is born","Besides building one of the first large scale analog computers, he was a social visionary talking about how technology can improve our lives. In the 1930s, he described an idea called Memex, a microfilm-based information retrieval system about the size of an office desk. He influenced Douglas Englebart with his writings.","Friday"];
Events[70]=["March","12","1994","The first Internet Cafe is open","Ivan Pope writes a proposal in response to being commissioned to develop an Internet event for 'Towards the Aesthetics of the Future' for the Institute of Contemporary Arts in London. This proposal describes a cafe with Internet access at each table. This cafe is opened during the weekend of the event.","Saturday"];
Events[71]=["March","13","1986","Microsoft stock becomes available to the public","The IPO had been months earlier and had raised $61 million.","Sunday"];
Events[72]=["March","14","1955","TRADIC is announced","Bell Labs has completed the first fully-transistorized computer, the TRADIC. Until this time, computers used either the slow, but reliable relay switches, or the fast, but failure-prone vacuum tubes. A side benefit was that the power needed to run the computer was orders of magnitude lower than what was needed previously.","Monday"];
Events[73]=["March","15","1985","The first internet domain name is registered","Symbolics.com was spun off the MIT Artificial Intelligence Lab and primarily designed, built and sold machines that were tuned to run LISP. Eventually, there were some disputes between Symbolics and the MIT Lab which prompted Richard Stallman to set up the GNU project.","Tuesday"];
Events[74]=["March","16","1995","Mortal Kombat II released for PCs","One of many arcade titles to increase gore and a sense of reality to fighting games. It was building on the success of the arcade version as well as the original Mortal Kombat game.","Wednesday"];
Events[75]=["March","17","1988","Apple sues Microsoft over Windows 2.0","Apple had licensed their GUI technology to Microsoft for Windows 1.0, but some of the improvements added in the 2.0 version 'crossed the line' and Apple filed a suit. Since Apple had essentially taken their ideas from the Xerox Alto and Star projects, Xerox decided to sue Apple on the same grounds. Both Apple and Xerox lost their suits.","Thursday"];
Events[76]=["March","18","1986","New York Times reports that an American Student tracked a Mir launch days before it was announced","Phillip Naranjo, a New Jersey High School student and member of Inertial Tracking and Orbital Calculations,  discovers transmissions in Cyrillic Code (essentially Morse Code for the Russian alphabet) that indicate that a launch is imminent. ","Friday"];
Events[77]=["March","19","1992","AOL goes public","More than a year before the Web is even conceived, AOL is beginning to set up a user base and receive funding.","Saturday"];
Events[78]=["March","20","1812","The 'Frame Breaking Act' receives royal approval in Britain","This act was intended to punish members of the Luddites who were destroying the automated looms as the looms represented a change in a way of life.  Lord Byron defends the Luddites to the House of Lords on one occasion. His daughter, Ada Lovelace, will go on to become considered the worlds first programmer.","Sunday"];
Events[79]=["March","21","2006","The Twitter project is started","Is it a blog? Is it text messaging for the web? Is it a newsfeed? Um... well... yes. Regardless, its popular enough to attract the Dalai Lama to it's list of users.","Monday"];
Events[80]=["March","22","1993","The Pentium Chip ships","In 1971, Intel creates the 4004, the first single-chip microprocessor, essentially suited to handheld calculators. This was ultimately followed by the 8086 processors used in the original IBM PC. This break from a number scheme to describe the chip was based on lawsuits that prohibited trademarking numbers for product names. ","Tuesday"];
Events[81]=["March","23","1928","Jean Sammet is born","Trained in Mathematics, she started as a teacher. When she made the move to the computer industry, she worked on many different projects. These include developing computer languages, writing a book on the history of computer languages and eventually becoming the president of the Association of Computing Machinery.","Wednesday"];
Events[82]=["March","24","1995","The first Zip drive is shipped","Iomega had previously released the more complicated Bernoulli Drive. The simpler Zip drive allowed for more inexpensive media to be produced. The Zip drive was never widely used because writeable CDs could store more and ultimately USB drives were cheaper and more convenient to use.","Thursday"];
Events[83]=["March","25","1995","The first Wiki is built","A small consulting organization creates this simple system to manage a community-built resource of various computer concepts and is still in use today.","Friday"];
Events[84]=["March","26","1976","Elizabeth II sends her first email","She was visiting an army base at the time, where this new communication method was in use. ","Saturday"];
Events[85]=["March","27","1990","Sierra and Broderbund cancel a previously-announced merger","Sierra Online, known for it's games and Broderbund, known for it's educational and utility titles would have made the largest producer of PC software at the time if the merger had completed. The merger was soon canceled when the two companies could not agree on the structure of the new organization.","Sunday"];
Events[86]=["March","28","1986","Article published on AIDS research that describe using computer graphics to assist with the research","Roche Laboratories published an article in Science magazine that discusses their use of computer graphics to assist in their research by modeling the structure of the AIDS protease molecule.","Monday"];
Events[87]=["March","29","1983","Tandy announces the Model 100","This portable computer had an 8-line, 40-column screen, a built-in modem, serial and parallel ports and included a text editor,  telecommunications package, schedule book, address book, and Microsoft BASIC. It runs on four AA batteries.","Tuesday"];
Events[88]=["March","30","1957","The 'stack' patent is filed","F.L. Bauer and K. Samelson filed a patent in Germany for a method of using a pushdown stack to perform arithmetic operations.","Wednesday"];
Events[89]=["March","31","1975","Ethernet patent is filed","The Ethernet standard is the physical aspect of networking. This includes the cables and the signal standards needed to pass a variety of protocols.","Thursday"];
Events[90]=["April","1","1985","The WELL is launched","The WELL (Whole Earth 'Lectronic Link) was owned by the Whole Earth Catalog publisher. It was one of the first 'virtual communities and initially was serving the readers and writers of the Whole Earth Catalog. It is currently run by Salon.com.","Friday"];
Events[91]=["April","2","1987","The IBM PS/2 is introduced","In an attempt to segment the market away from it's competitors, new features were added such as the 1.44Mb floppy and the VGA display standard. From an OS perspective, the intent was to make OS/2 the default, but it wasn't ready at the time the hardware was, so DOS, AIX and Windows were all vying for the de facto standard.","Saturday"];
Events[92]=["April","3","1986","The first IBM laptop is released","The IBM PC Convertible had two 720Kb floppy drives and a monochrome monitor capable of emulating CGA graphics. While there was a 'portable' computer that was released earlier, this version looks more like what we are used to when we think of a laptop. ","Sunday"];
Events[93]=["April","4"," ","Isodorus de Sevilla day of celebration","Isodorus de Sevilla is the unofficial patron saint of the Internet. Born around the year 560, he eventually became the Bishop of Seville. He is known for working diligently to keep the Gothic kingdom together based on his conviction that all forms of knowledge can be used for a greater good.","Monday"];
Events[94]=["April","5","1982","The New York Times describes the error embedded in a chip that is affecting new PCs","Microsoft had provided BASIC embedded in a ROM chip and one of the subroutines was faulty. This resulted in some calculations being wrong. The problem was that the error was on code embedded on a chip and not on the hard drive.","Tuesday"];
Events[95]=["April","6","1972","Cray Research Opens","After more than twenty years building computers, Seymour Cray opens his own lab in Chippewa Falls, Wisconsin. His rationale for his designs is summarized in a quote attributed to him 'If you were plowing a field, which would you rather use: Two strong oxen or 1024 chickens?' ","Wednesday"];
Events[96]=["April","7","1969","RFC 1 was published","The RFC (Request for Comments) document was a somewhat standard mechanism for the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) to use for making proposals on improvements and changes to the internet. While not standards, these documents are often considered to reflect the spirit of the protocol, if not the complete set of guidelines.","Thursday"];
Events[97]=["April","8","1991","The Sun Microsystems team working on Java moves to an off-site lab to start their work in earnest","In order to maintain secrecy, the core group of the Oak Development Project moves out of the main facility to work on what will become the Java language.","Friday"];
Events[98]=["April","9","1919","Presper Eckert is born","Presper Eckert is one of the principle designers of the ENIAC. Along with John Mauchly, they worked on the ENIAC from 1943 to 1946. Both had used Vanevar Bush's electro-mechanical Difference Engine to perform calculations, but wanted to do more work in less time.","Saturday"];
Events[99]=["April","10","1981","Space shuttle maiden flight is grounded due to software bug","The failure was ultimately traced back to two different organizations implementing the same design for two parts of the redundant system that were intended to be identical. A small difference in interpretation caused the initialization to fail. Two days later, the system was fixed and on April 12, 1981, the Columbia made it's first voyage.","Sunday"];
Events[100]=["April","11","2000","RIM releases their Wireless Computer","This was released a couple of years before the Blackberry where the computer and the cell phone were merged.","Monday"];
Events[101]=["April","12","1979","Earliest known use of emoticons for email","Kevin MacKenzie suggested that emoticons :-), :-( and others be used to indicate tone and intent within email messages. This suggestion was posted in the CMU BBS (and not in an email) ;-)","Tuesday"];
Events[102]=["April","13","1909","Stan Ulam is born","Stan Ulam and his brother Adam defect to the United States while visiting the US as a Harvard Junior Fellow just before the start of World War II. He receives his PhD and after teaching at Harvard and the University of Wisconsin, Ulam joins The Manhattan Projec where he meets John Von Neumann.","Wednesday"];
Events[103]=["April","14","2004","Lindows becomes Linspire","A company called 'Lindows, Inc.' planned to release a version of Linux that was fully compatible with Windows applications. Microsoft eventually sued them and forced them to change their name. The goal of building a windows-compatible operating system is still underway and not yet fully realized.","Thursday"];
Events[104]=["April","15","1977","The First Annual West Coast Computer Faire is held","This event was held at the Brooks Civic Auditorium in San Francisco. Nearly thirteen thousand people attended this event. The rights to the Faire were eventually sold to COMDEX. Eventually COMDEX filed for bankruptcy and held no more conventions.","Friday"];
Events[105]=["April","16","1971","The FTP RFC is submitted","The File Transfer Protocol (FTP) is proposed in Request for Comment (RFC) 114. Several revisions follow this first version.","Saturday"];
Events[106]=["April","17","1944","The Mark I computer is operational","The president of Harvard University, James Conant sends a letter to Thomas Watson Sr. the founder of IBM to let him know that the Mark I was in operation. This project combined the efforts of the US Governemnt, Universities and Corporations in an effort to assist with the war effort.","Sunday"];
Events[107]=["April","18","2005","Adobe announces bid for Macromedia","While Adobe was better known for making electronic versions of paper documents, Macromedia was known for web site design applications. This merger cost about $3.4 billion dollars.","Monday"];
Events[108]=["April","19","1965","Moore's Law is proposed","Gordon Moore publishes an article in Electronic Magazine that proposes that computing power has been roughly doubling every 12 months due to research and improvements in the field and that this trend is likely to continue in the future. In 1975, this is revised to every 18 months and is termed to be 'Moore's Law'.","Tuesday"];
Events[109]=["April","20","1998","At a public demonstration of the new Windows 98, Bill Gates crashes the computer","While demonstrating the 'plug and play' feature by adding a scanner to the system while it is running, the computer crashes and displays the 'Blue Screen of Death' (BSOD) indicating a severe system failure has occurred. ","Wednesday"];
Events[110]=["April","21","1988","Tandy announces plans to produce IBM PS/2 clones","A year after the IBM PS/2 is announced, Tandy announces they will license the patents for the new technologies included with the PS/2 and produce a clone. Within five years, IBM will loose it's share of the PS/2 market, effectively failing to meet the goals for producing this line in the first place.","Thursday"];
Events[111]=["April","22","2002","The Xanadu Project publishes it's first FAQ","While publishing a FAQ is not new, publishing one for a project that is more than 30 years old is unique. By 2007, it was the oldest vaporware product, only to lose that title when it actually released it's first version. This made it the software product that spent the longest time in development (at least 35 years) before it's first release.","Friday"];
Events[112]=["April","23","1996","Internet Explorer 2.0 for Mac is released","This browser from Microsoft comes a year before Netscape has a Mac version and nearly six years before Apple will release it's own Safari browser. ","Saturday"];
Events[113]=["April","24","1981","The IBM PC is introduced","While not the first personal computer, it establishes the basis for future PC systems. ","Sunday"];
Events[114]=["April","25","1961","Patent awarded for the Integrated Circuit","Robert Noyce and Jack Kilby both had similar ideas on how to accomplish this. Kilby used germanium while Noyce used Silicon. There was a long dispute about who was the rightful inventor. Today, we have seen the silicon version prevail.","Monday"];
Events[115]=["April","26","2001","The Media Marketing Accountability Act is introduced","US Senators Joe Lieberman and Herb Kohl introduced the MMAA legislation to authorize the FTC to prosecute entertainment companies that market adult-related media to children. This bill was introduced and referred to committee, but not taken up by the committee and was not passed into law.","Tuesday"];
Events[116]=["April","27","1977","Hobby Computer Club forms","Not to be confused with the Homebrew Computer Club formed two years earlier, the HCC (Hobby Computer Club) was formed in the Netherlands where it still exists today and has over 180,000 members.","Wednesday"];
Events[117]=["April","28","1994","US producers of flat-screen computer monitors receive subsidies","President Clinton announces a program to provide assistance to US companies that produce flat-panel displays. These displays will be used for military equipment by the Department of Defense and will ultimately allow the US to take over part of the market dominated by the Japanese, who had 95% of the flat-screen market at the time.","Thursday"];
Events[118]=["April","29","1989","First time a computer animation wins an Academy Award","Pixar's 'Tin Toy' receives an Academy Award for Animated Short Film.","Friday"];
Events[119]=["April","30","1971","The Telnet RFC is submitted","While not the current version, this version discusses the characteristics of being able to log into a computer on the network in a consistent way. For all appearances, it's as if you have a command prompt on your local system, but in reality, the computer could be anywhere your network can reach.","Saturday"];
Events[120]=["May","1","1978","Earliest record of email spam","A DEC marketing representative sent out an email to apparently any email address he could find to announce a presentation. This led to a response from a senior administrator saying that this behavior violated the terms of use for the ARPANET (this is before the Internet) and that 'steps were being taken'.","Sunday"];
Events[121]=["May","2","1955","Dave Winer is born","Dave Winer contributed to several early versions of the RSS format. While he did not conceive of the standard, he did take the initial standard developed at Netscape and made modifications. There is apparently an ongoing dispute of who owns the 'real' version of RSS (and what it 'really' stands for).","Monday"];
Events[122]=["May","3","1984","Dell Computer is founded","While initially selling exclusively in the Personal Computer market, they have branched out to consumer electronics and have consistently outpaced the S&P 500 in terms of year-to-year growth.","Tuesday"];
Events[123]=["May","4","1536","One of the earliest uses of the @ symbol","A Florentine merchant Fancesco Lapi uses the @ symbol in a letter to describe some cargo he was expecting. The symbol is also found some fifty years earlier, and the specific date of it's first usage must be earlier than that even.","Wednesday"];
Events[124]=["May","5","1952","Idea for integrated circuit is proposed","G.W.A. Drummer of the British Royal Radar Establishment proposed the idea of a single block of semi-conductive material performing multiple functions. It wasn't until the late 1950s that Jack Kilby and Robert Noyce came up with working prototypes.","Thursday"];
Events[125]=["May","6","1998","The iMac is released","In an apparent effort to go back to a combined monitor and CPU that symbolized the original Apple Mac computers, this revision sports multiple colors and a stylish design. Each successive iMac design is unique and provides an distinction between the Mac systems and typical PCs.","Friday"];
Events[126]=["May","7","1954","The IBM 704 is introduced, the first computer to have a dot-matrix printer","While the printer is not available at the time the 704 is released, it is ready within the next four years.","Saturday"];
Events[127]=["May","8","1995","National Network of newspaper publishers is formed to consolidate online news services","The New Century Network is formed by the New York Times and eight other newspaper publishers.  Three years and some $25 million dollars later, the company is disbanded, much to the relief of some senior executives.","Sunday"];
Events[128]=["May","9","1967","New datacenter dedicated for the National Center for Atmospheric Research in Boulder Colorado","The National Center for Atmospheric Research in Boulder Colorado used computers and other technology to investigate weather patterns. This new building was designed by the renowned I.M. Pei.","Monday"];
Events[129]=["May","10","","National Abacus Day in Japan","The versatility of the abacus to perform not only addition and subtraction, but multiplication and division properly show that this seemingly simple device deserves to have it's own day of celebration.","Tuesday"];
Events[130]=["May","11","1997","Gary Kasparov resigns against IBM's chess computer, Deep Blue","Gary Kasparov is the worlds best self-promoting chess player, if not the best chess player of all time. On move 19 of game 6 against Deep Blue, he resigns the game. This is the first time a computer has beaten a chess master in tournament conditions.","Wednesday"];
Events[131]=["May","12","1987","The first commercial ISP is founded","UUNET Communication services is founded by Richard Adams. The market for Internet Service Providers is now considered almost a commodity.","Thursday"];
Events[132]=["May","13","1980","The Ethernet network specification is announced","In a joint venture between Xerox, Digital Equipment and Intel, the Ethernet specification is built and announced.","Friday"];
Events[133]=["May","14","1948","The RAND corporation is created","Originally a research department for McDonnel Douglas performing lots of technology research for them and other military corporations, the RAND corporation is separated from McDonnel Douglas to form it's own non-profit organization.","Saturday"];
Events[134]=["May","15","2004","Largest Known (at the time) Prime Number is Found","Josh Findley used a 2.4 Ghz Pentium processor to find this Mersenne Prime. These are of the form (2 to some prime integer power)-1. In this case the power of two is 24,036,583 (which is prime). Since then there have been more found. This pattern for finding primes has existed since at least the 4th century.","Sunday"];
Events[135]=["May","16","1938","Ivan Sutherland is born","He is best known for developing Sketchpad, noted as the first popular project in computer graphics in the 1960s. He went on to serve in academia, corporate and venture capitol roles for many organizations.","Monday"];
Events[136]=["May","17","2002","Napster announces it will be acquired","In less than three years, Napster was conceived, popularized, sued and was now effectively bankrupt and unable to act with impunity with music files.  They are purchased by Bertelsmann for $85 million dollars. File sharing services still exist, though are less popular than they once were.","Tuesday"];
Events[137]=["May","18","1998","The US Justice Department files an Antitrust Lawsuit Against Microsoft","The claim is that Microsoft abused its monopoly power in regards to the sale of their operating systems and bundling it with a web browser. A settlement was ultimately reached where Microsoft agreed to publish it's program interfaces to allow 3rd party applications to have essentially the same access to the system as Internet Explorer.","Wednesday"];
Events[138]=["May","19","2001","The first Apple Store is launched","In a move to more specifically target the Apple brand to consumers, Apple Corporation launched it's first Apple Store in Mclean, Virginia. This not only provides a direct sales opportunity, but allows for specific marketing campaigns to be well-coordinated in key markets.","Thursday"];
Events[139]=["May","20","1875","The International Bureau of Weights and Measures is formed","Based in France, the Bureau International des Poids et Meausres (BIPM) was established as the keeper of the official standards for the metric system. The BIPM is also responsible for consolidating the member nation's official time as the UTC, also known as the Coordinated Universal Time clock.","Friday"];
Events[140]=["May","21","1962","First software patent filed","This is arguably the first (or one of the first) patents that is considered to be a software patent. It was filed in Britain as a method for solving linear programming problems. Since then, software has been specifically excluded from the patent process.","Saturday"];
Events[141]=["May","22","1980","Pac Man is released in Japan","One of the most popular early video games. It inspired spin-offs, songs, a cartoon show and much more. It was originally called 'Puckman' as a play on the word 'paku-paku taberu' in Japanese that means something to the effect of flapping your mouth open and closed. By the time the game is released in the US, the name is Pacman.","Sunday"];
Events[142]=["May","23","1995","The Java Programming Language is announced","Sun Microsystems envisioned a computer language that was 'Write once, run anywhere'.  Developers would write and compile their applications to bytecode, a halfway point between an executable program and source code. This bytecode would be run through a Java virtual machine that would execute the application.","Monday"];
Events[143]=["May","24","2007","twitdir is launched","Since being started the year before, a Twitter User Directory is launched, allowing for searching of users. In the first four years of it's existence, it's managed to increase usage to 4 billion tweets a quarter.","Tuesday"];
Events[144]=["May","25","1994","The first World Wide Web Conference is held","The same folks that are responsible for the Large Hadron Collier hosted the first World Wide Web Conference.  This whole project for creating the world wide web stemmed from the problem of consolidating research from multiple sources and making it available on-site from any system.","Wednesday"];
Events[145]=["May","26","1995","Bill Gates sends a memo 'The Internet Tidal Wave'","Some 18 months after Tim Berners-Lee creates the first web site and web server, Bill Gates announces that this platform will be the next big thing for Personal Computing. This is the beginning of Microsoft's formal push to embrace the Internet within it's products. ","Thursday"];
Events[146]=["May","27","1843","The fax machine patent is filed","You may have thought that the fax machine was relatively new, but this early version shows that not only did fax machines predate photocopiers, they pre-dated the telephone. This version was not practical for regular use since the quality of the images were poor. ","Friday"];
Events[147]=["May","28","1959","Committee to develop COBOL is formed","While the name 'COBOL' won't be agreed upon for several months, this first meeting is held at the Pentagon. A few weeks earlier, a group of computer users and corporations, along with the US Department of Defense planned to organize a committee to develop a new computer language.","Saturday"];
Events[148]=["May","29","1996","The first Java conference is held","Just one year after the Java programming language being announced and weeks after the SDK being released, the first Java conference is held. There were more than 6000 attendees.","Sunday"];
Events[149]=["May","30","1996","AT&T announces Video Phone Call system","This is not the first video phone system. However, it does indicate an improved use of limited resources by allowing video and audio to both be used over phone wire.","Monday"];
Events[150]=["May","31","1932","Jay Glenn Miner is born","Miner received his Electrical Engineering degree in 1959 and started his career on medical devices. He later joined Atari and eventually started a new venture. After some funding issues, they entered into an agreement with Commodore to purchase the rights to their work. This ultimately resulted in the creation of the Amiga computer. ","Tuesday"];
Events[151]=["June","1","1981","Imagic is formed","Former employees of Atari and Mattel Electronics built a company to be a 3rd party developer of Atari 2600 games. Probably their first big hit was 'Missile Command'.","Wednesday"];
Events[152]=["June","2","2003","Toontown Online is launched","Walt Disney's foray into the MMORPG (Massively Multiplayer, Online Role--Playing Game) world is called Toontown Online. While designed to limit the hours it could be used and other parent-friendly features, it ultimately fails to draw enough users to keep it viable.","Thursday"];
Events[153]=["June","3","1983","The movie 'War Games' is released in the US","One of the first 'hacker' movies shows a teen that connects to a military mainframe and inadvertently uses a system capable of launching nuclear weapons.","Friday"];
Events[154]=["June","4","1996","Ariane 5 self-destructs in response to software bug","The Ariane 5 rocket was built to deliver geostationary devices to outer space. Software from the Ariane 4 was re-used, but due to the faster rockets used, a previously-unknown bug was found in one of the calculation routines. When this bug crashed the system, this triggered the self-destruct sequence.","Saturday"];
Events[155]=["June","5","1833","Ada Lovelace meets Charles Babbage","Ada's father, Lord Byron once expressed sympathies for the Luddites in the British House of Lords. While Charles Babbage was promoting his Difference Engine, he asked Ada to transcribe a paper into English. She adds her own examples of how the machine could be configured, making her arguably the first programmer.","Sunday"];
Events[156]=["June","6","1850","Karl Ferdinand Braun is born","Arguably the father of the CRT and wifi. In 1897, he publishes a paper describing a rudimentary CRT.  He also, patented the idea of a crystal diode rectifier, an essential component for wireless telegraphy (telegraph using radio waves). Wireless telegraphy was short-lived, but is effectively the predecessor of wifi technology.","Monday"];
Events[157]=["June","7","1954","Alan Turing dies","Alan Turing, computer pioneer and leading researcher on cryptanalysis during World War II commits suicide after years of legal proceedings for being homosexual. Gay and transgender people have since become better accepted as evidenced by Lynn Conway, who co-wrote the seminal book on chip design in 1978. This book built upon her work from the 1960s at IBM, where she was fired for undergoing transgender medical treatments. In 1999, she began publicly acknowledging her history and is now generally accepted by her peers and her community.","Tuesday"];
Events[158]=["June","8","1978","The Intel 8086 processor is released","This processor's instruction set is at the core of many modern intel-based computers. The instruction set proved to be so successful and popular that it has been difficult to justify any major modifications until recently. This chip follows from the 8080 which follows from the 8008 which follows from the first microprocessor the 4004.","Wednesday"];
Events[159]=["June","9","2006","Brain Age is released in Europe","This Nintendo DS cartridge is one of the most successful titles to address improvement of brain functioning. While not as popular in Europe as it was in Japan, it still sold hundreds of thousands of copies in the first few months.","Thursday"];
Events[160]=["June","10","1977","The first Apple II ships","Less than a week after going on sale, the first Apple II computer is shipped. The popularity of the Apple II will continue well into the 1990s due to it's simple interface and affordable pricing.","Friday"];
Events[161]=["June","11","1978","The 'Speak & Spell' is announced","With this consumer-focused product, Texas Instruments shows some of their impressive technology skills. This device was the first single-chip capable of reproducing the human voice. Touted as an educational device, it would ask the user to spell a word that it would say and then say a word the user would spell.","Saturday"];
Events[162]=["June","12","1985","FidoNet starts to use phone numbers as node names for the first time","FidoNet is a grass-roots network that connects BBS systems and allows for messages and email to be passed around. It was originally popularized at a time when internet access was not available outside universities and before AOL, Prodigy and other information services were popular. The FidoNet system is still around today.","Sunday"];
Events[163]=["June","13","1993","Time Warner, Microsoft and Tele-Communications Inc. announce joint venture for TV-based information service company","The web is only three years old at this time and delivering information through the television was the approach of choice for these tech and content juggernauts. However, within two years, this project is abandoned and Bill Gates is pushing the World Wide Web as the biggest thing for PCs, effectively killing the deal.","Monday"];
Events[164]=["June","14","1951","US Census Bureau get's it's first electronic computer","Ever since Herman Hollerith's Tabulating Machine was used for the 1890 US census, the US Census Bureau was constantly trying to keep up with the increasingly large amount of data. On this day, they get their first commercially-available computer, the UNIVAC I.","Tuesday"];
Events[165]=["June","15","1949","The idea for Core memory is recorded by Jay Forrester","In the first steps to a working prototype, Jay Forrester of MIT writes down his notes on how it could work. For the next quarter century, this type of memory was used and eventually phased out with the semi-conductor technology still in use today.","Wednesday"];
Events[166]=["June","16","1911","IBM is formed","Herman Hollerith's company that built the tabulating machines used in the 1890 census had existed since 1886. It incorporates on this day as Computing Tabulating Recording Corporation. It won't take the IBM name for another six years.","Thursday"];
Events[167]=["June","17","1980","Atari registers copyright for games","Atari registers a Copyright for two games, 'Asteroids' and 'Lunar Landar'. This is a first for computer games.","Friday"];
Events[168]=["June","18","1974","The Intel 8080 processor is released","This has been called the first 'practical' microprocessor. It's the predecessor of the 8086, which instruction set has been the basis for PC architectures through the boom era of personal computing. The 8080 processor follows 4004 and 8008 processors, which are arguably the first microprocessors.","Saturday"];
Events[169]=["June","19","2000","Windows ME is released to computer manufacturers","Largely viewed as a disaster in marketing and engineering, this operating system was a minor update to Windows 98 and was seen as the consumer alternative to the business-focused Windows 2000 operating system. It was intended to be seen as 'new', when in reality, it included mostly some new applications.","Sunday"];
Events[170]=["June","20","1950","The (US) National Bureau of Standards dedicates the SEAC","The SEAC (Standards Eastern Automatic Computer) used the more reliable diode instead of the vacuum tube. This was also the United State's first stored-program computer, meaning that you didn't need to hard-wire the program to be able to run it, you could load the program into memory and run it.","Monday"];
Events[171]=["June","21","1948","The first stored computer program is run","Before this time, programs were hard-wired into the computer. Changing the program meant literally changing wires. At this time in Britain, that changed with the ability to store the program inside the computer to be modified making changes much easier.","Tuesday"];
Events[172]=["June","22","1979","InfoCom is incorporated","Bringing us such interactive fiction games as Zork and Planetfall, Infocom was incorporated by a group from MIT. The interactive fiction type of game allows the user to type in commands and the game would respond. For example,typing 'Open the mailbox', would be responded to with 'Opening the small mailbox reveals a leaflet'.","Wednesday"];
Events[173]=["June","23","1902","Howard Engstrom is born","Howard Engstrom joined the Navy's CSAW (Communications Supplementary Activities - Washington) to work on cryptography and was encouraged to start a private company to do this research. Eventually, Engineering Research Associates was formed where the UNIVAC computers for Remington Rand were designed.","Thursday"];
Events[174]=["June","24","2002","The Sharp Zarus SL-A300 is introduced","This handheld computer featured the Linux operating system, a 200Mhz processor 64Mb RAM 320x240 display and a SD slot for storage. ","Friday"];
Events[175]=["June","25","1984","First flight of Discovery delayed due to  software bug","At three seconds before launch, the shutdown signal is sent due to a software bug.Once in orbit, an icicle of urine formed where waste was ejected from the shuttle. A robot maneuver was created to attempt to break off the pee-cicle, but it damaged one of the tiles and the crew was unable to use the toilet for the remainder of the mission.","Saturday"];
Events[176]=["June","26","1974","First commercial use of the Bar Code","At a March supermarket in Troy, Ohio, a computer connected to a laser reader read a Bar Code. The system identified the item and automatically gave the price. It will be a few more decades before the self-serve line is added to grocery stores.","Sunday"];
Events[177]=["June","27","1950","The earliest movie to show a functioning computer","Desitnation Moon' is released. In it, a GE Differential Analyzer is shown. While it is essentially an analog computer, it does perform complex calculations very quickly.","Monday"];
Events[178]=["June","28","1974","Vannevar Bush dies"," In 1945, he published 'As We May Think' in the Atlanta Journal, where he discussed the use of information access machines. This article was read by Douglas Englebart and inspired him to do many things, such as 'The Mother of All Demos' in 1968.","Tuesday"];
Events[179]=["June","29","1992","Silicon Graphics and MIPS merge","In the 1980s, Silicon Graphics was the primary producer of computer systems needing graphics capabilities. With Personal Computers, the need for a specialized computer was declining. Buying the company, MIPS, that made the processor for their systems seemed like a good move, but it was essentially the beginning of the end.","Wednesday"];
Events[180]=["June","30","2008","The last day for PC makers to install Windows XP by default","Windows XP has been out since 2001 and it turned out to be too much of a good thing. When Windows Vista was released, very few wanted to change from a system that was generally useful and stable. In a move to force users to upgrade to the next operating system, this end-of-life date was set.","Thursday"];
Events[181]=["July","1","1984","Neuromancer is released","Although William Gibson uses the term 'cyberspace' in an earlier short story, this is its first use in a book, six years before the world wide web exists. The author went on to write many other short stories and books, including 'Difference Engine' where he and Bruce Sterling imagine the information age occurred a hundred years earlier.","Friday"];
Events[182]=["July","2","1953","The IBM Model 650 is announced","This popular computer model was in service for much of the 1950s. It featured a magnetic drum to store data as well as accept punched cards for input. The punched card idea for calculation dates back to Herman Hollerith's tabulating machine used in the 1890 census. That company eventually became IBM.","Saturday"];
Events[183]=["July","3","1903","First communications cable across the Pacific is laid","The cable connects Hawaii (before it was a state), Midway, Guam and Manila. The first signal is sent the next day after being tested on this day.","Sunday"];
Events[184]=["July","4","1956","The first computer to accept input from a keyboard","The Whirlwind computer had been completed five years earlier and is just now allowing input from a keyboard. Until now, only punched cards were used. Another first for the Whirlwind is 'core memory'. ","Monday"];
Events[185]=["July","5","1993","On the internet, nobody knows you're a dog' appears in the New Yorker","Peter Steiner had been working at The New Yorker for about fifteen years at the time and wasn't intending to make a statement. However, once popularized, it took on a life of its own. ","Tuesday"];
Events[186]=["July","6","1996","AOL settles lawsuits for misleading subscribers","In California, this class action lawsuit accused AOL of  misleading consumers about the costs of their service. The settlement resulted in AOL providing $22 million in rebates and free online time, or roughly $3.67 for each of their 6 million subscribers.","Wednesday"];
Events[187]=["July","7","1752","Joseph-Marie Jacquard is born","The Jacquard loom is invented about 1801. This pioneered the use of punched cards for storing instructions. Within ten years, this invention was attacked because of the huge societal change that resulted from the industrial revolution.  By 1890, Herman Hollerith uses punched cards for a machine to tabulate the US census.","Thursday"];
Events[188]=["July","8","1946","U of Pennsylvania launches computing summer school","The Moore School of Electrical Engineering offered a free and public set of lectures. Wildly popular, these lectures sparked the ideas for the EDSAC, BINAC, and, later, the AVIDAC.","Friday"];
Events[189]=["July","9","1982","The movie 'Tron' is released","This science fiction story is about a computer hacker being digitally added as a program to a mainframe system to help prove his assertions that he is the creator of the games being sold by a rival co-worker who claimed the ideas are his own.","Saturday"];
Events[190]=["July ","10","1999","Back Orifice 2000 is released","The self-described hacker group 'Cult of the Dead Cow', released Back Orifice 2000 (aka BO2K). The use of this tool was a composite of known vulnerabilities for Windows 95 and Windows 98 that they hoped could run against Windows 2000. This prompted several BO2K detection tools to be released such as BoDetect.","Sunday"];
Events[191]=["July","11","1994","Gary Kildall dies","While computer pioneers are not well known to participate in bar brawls, let alone die in one, this is what happened to Gary Kildall. Of his many achievements, he is known for the CP/M operating system which the Microsoft DOS Operating System is heavily influenced by.","Monday"];
Events[192]=["July","12","1993","Energy Star initiative is panned","The Energy Star initiative rates electronic equipment for it's energy efficiency. Mike Feibus likens it to a 'Lite' label on a package of bacon in an article in the 'Microprocessor Report'.","Tuesday"];
Events[193]=["July","13","1998","Software bug leaves Navy 'Smart Ship'  dead in the water","In an attempt to promote the stability and utility of the Windows NT platform, a new 'Smart Ship' was fitted with a Windows NT-based network. When one of the systems crashes, a domino-effect takes down all critical systems, leaving the ship unable to move for about an hour.","Wednesday"];
Events[194]=["July","14","1995","Windows 95 source code is 'frozen'","This is the first version of Microsoft's operating systems after the Windows 3.1 release and shows a huge improvement in the User Interface. 'Freezing' the source code means no more changes can be made before shipping it to the computer manufacturers for installation.","Thursday"];
Events[195]=["July","15","2000","C# is announced","Both C and C++ are coordinated by the ANSI and ISO organizations. C# (pronounced 'C sharp') is standardized by ECMA. Microsoft was one of the originating companies to support and develop this standard and has gone on to implement closed libraries that are used within this standard.","Friday"];
Events[196]=["July","16","2004","The first virus targeting Windows CE appears","Viruses targeted at personal computers and servers are not new. Targeting handheld devices running Windows CE is new. Now that handheld devices are accessing the internet, any vulnerabilities can be leveraged and potentially exploited.","Saturday"];
Events[197]=["July","17","1970","The First TV game console demo","While the 'Brown Box' will never be produced commercially, the rights to the technology will be purchased by Magnavox for the Magnavox Odyssey, which did become the first commercial TV game console in 1972, even before pong.","Sunday"];
Events[198]=["July","18","1968","Intel is incorporated","Within two years, they will release the first microprocessor, within ten years, they will release the 8086 chip, whose instruction set was used for decades for the processors for most personal computers.","Monday"];
Events[199]=["July","19","2001","The Playstation 2 hard drive is released","The first video game consoles in the 1970s either had built-in games or used cartridges with electronic components. In the late 1980s, CD-ROM drives were used. This is the first major game console to support a hard drive for saving game data and even some games. ","Tuesday"];
Events[200]=["July","20","1976","First Robot Lands on Mars","The Viking I lands on Mars to explore the surface. Among it's capabilities was to perform soil analysis and send back data to help determine the likelihood of life as well as detailed images.","Wednesday"];
Events[201]=["July","21","1938","Paul Allaire is born","Allaire starts at Xerox in 1966 before the famous PARC research center is created and goes on to be company president, then CEO and finally chairman. During his leadership, Xerox wins top quality awards including the Deming Prize in Japan, the Baldrige Award in the U.S. and the European Quality Award.","Thursday"];
Events[202]=["July","22","1962","The Mariner 1 rocket is forced to self-destruct","After deviating from it's intended flight path, Mission Control sends a self-destruct command. The cause was determined to be an error in transcribing a hand-written formula to computer code. This error effectively caused normal variations in speed to be mis-interpreted as critical that took the rocket off course.","Friday"];
Events[203]=["July","23","1930","Daniel McCracken is born","McCracken was trained in Mathematics and Chemistry, but started in the computer industry in 1951. While working for General Electric, he trained computer users on various aspects of the systems being created. He is well known for developing many teaching materials, including the first textbook on the language FORTRAN.","Saturday"];
Events[204]=["July","24","1951","John Bardeen leaves AT&T Labs","One of the inventors of the transistor, John Bardeen, notified AT&T that he would be leaving. He was becoming increasingly dissatisfied with his relationship with the other contributor to inventing the transistor, William Shockley. He left for a position in academia. John Bardeen is the only person to win the Nobel Prize in Physics twice.","Sunday"];
Events[205]=["July","25","2008","Randy Pausch dies","The creator of the Alice programming tool for kids spent much of his career on Human-Computer Interaction. Less than two years before his death, he learned that he had a terminal case of pancreatic cancer. He went on to speak publicly with a message of hope in his 'Last Lecture' series.","Monday"];
Events[206]=["July","26","1984","Zork I has it's final release","Zork is the most popular game in the interactive fiction genre. The gameplay was relatively simple in that the player would read a description of what their environment was like and would type in the commands of what they wanted to do. While not the last in the series, this is the last release of the 'original' Zork. ","Tuesday"];
Events[207]=["July","27","1967","First electronic ATM installed in London","There are many claims to the first Automated Teller Machine installation. This one claim separates itself from others by being connected to the user's bank account and by dispensing cash. Before this time, there were machines that would dispense cash, but would charge it to your credit card. ","Wednesday"];
Events[208]=["July","28","1965","The Voskhod spacecraft schedule is announced","The Voskhod 'Sunrise' program was the Soviet Union's human spaceflight program. Months earlier, an existing Voskhod flight experienced a failure of the on-board computer during landing, causing it to be hundreds of kilometers off course. This program provided the Soviets many firsts in space travel.","Thursday"];
Events[209]=["July","29","1975","First known use of the word 'Micro-soft'","Earlier that year while Bill Gates is a Sophomore at Harvard, he and Paul Allan produce a version of BASIC for the Altair, the first 'personal computer' with the first simple programming language. They license this to MITS and eventually use the name Micro-soft to refer to this new venture in creating software.","Friday"];
Events[210]=["July","30","1940","Clive Sinclair is born","Coming from a line of creative engineers, Clive Sinclair is interested in electronics from a very young age. He produces electronic kits, books on electronics, pocket calculators, and the ZX Spectrum in the early 1980s. The ZX Spectrum allowed many to get their first experience with computers.","Saturday"];
Events[211]=["July","31","1980","Radio Shack introduces several computers","The TRS-80 Model III, the Color Computer and the TRS-80 Pocket Computer are all announced on this day. While these are not the first lines of computers to be offered by Radio Shack, they do offer access to computers for personal use and not business class machines typically available. These models pre-date the IBM PC by about a year.","Sunday"];
Events[212]=["August","1","1967","Grace Hopper recalled to active duty at the age of 70","Her abilities were not in combat, but in developing compilers. In this case, she was being asked to coordinate the standardization of COBOL. As early as 1952, she began work on translating english text to programs, which was not accepted at the time as a proper way to program computers. ","Monday"];
Events[213]=["August","2","1993","The Apple Newton is launched","The Apple Newton was the first device to refer to itself as a PDA (Personal Digital Assistant). This device used a pen to accept handwriting input for taking notes. The initial versions were so notoriously bad that one Simpson's episode showed the bully Nelson's to-do entry (on a Newton-like device) 'Beat up Martin' get interpreted as 'Eat up Martha'. ","Tuesday"];
Events[214]=["August","3","1977","The TRS-80 is introduced","This personal computer was introduced by Radio Shack four years before the IBM-PC was announced. This first model was one of the most popular because it was well marketed in existing stores. It  sold a quarter of a million units over it's 4 year lifespan. Reminiscing users will fondly remember their so-called 'Trash 80's.","Wednesday"];
Events[215]=["August","4","2005","The first wiki conference is held","Wikimania 2005: The First International Wikimedia Conference was held in Frankfurt. The first wiki was installed ten years earlier as a simple way to manage content for c2.com. ","Thursday"];
Events[216]=["August","5","1989","The Video Toaster is on display at SiGGRAPH","SIGGRAPH is the premiere conference on computer graphics tools and techniques. The Video Toaster was one of the first professional-quality add-ons for a personal computer that could effectively produce video. This system would not edit the video from the hard drive, but it could be programmed to operate video tape players for editing the video.","Friday"];
Events[217]=["August","6","1997","Apple announces an alliance with Microsoft","At the Macworld Expo, Steve Jobs and Bill Gates announce a five year alliance. Microsoft Office will be built for the Mac platform and Internet Explorer will be made the default browser for the Mac during these five years. This agreement also required that Larry Ellison of Oracle would be removed from Apple's board.","Saturday"];
Events[218]=["August","7","1970","Fist computer chess tournament","The ACM (Association of Computing Machinery) sponsored what is considered the first computer chess tournament. During these first few tournaments, these chess programs were only suitable for playing each other. But within the next 6-8 years, the chess masters were being beaten by newer versions of these same programs.","Sunday"];
Events[219]=["August","8","1995","Netscape Communications becomes a public company","Netscape was one of the first suites of web-based communication tools including the Netscape web browser,  email client, news reader, calendar application and more.","Monday"];
Events[220]=["August","9","1927","Marvin Minsky was born","He co-founded the MIT Artificial Intelligence lab. He has been at MIT for over fifty years and has greatly influenced the direction of Artificial Intelligence.","Tuesday"];
Events[221]=["August","10","1929","Pierre Fatou dies","Pierre Fatou was a French Mathematician that defined the formulas that Benoit Mandelbrot used in later years to 'discover' the Mandelbrot set and other fractals. The most common visualization of fractals are the paisley-looking multi-colored images generated by computers.","Wednesday"];
Events[222]=["August","11","1987","HyperCard is introduced at the Macworld Expo","Hypercard was a massive change in how computer programs (called stacks) were written. It provided a simple method for placing user interface components such as buttons and textboxes. These stacks could be easily shared between users.","Thursday"];
Events[223]=["August","12","1981","The IBM PC is released","Somewhat late to the personal computer market, IBM makes a shift from the larger business-class computers to the smaller personal computer market. Very quickly though, this form factor provided the de-facto standard for personal computers, with only the Macintosh line being able to survive since then.","Friday"];
Events[224]=["August","13","1999","The Matrix is released","This movie features a world where aliens have taken over the Earth and have enslaved the humans by implanting an interface that makes them believe they are living in a seemingly normal world as it existed prior to the alien's arrival. However, there are a few humans that are able to overcome this illusion and see the simulation for what it is.","Saturday"];
Events[225]=["August","14","1984","The EGA computer graphics standard is announced","This was the first personal computer color video standard to have a higher resolution than broadcast television. It came at a cost though. A $200 memory upgrade was required and then the card itself was over $500.","Sunday"];
Events[226]=["August","15","1984","Amiga is purchased by Commodore","Before their first system was released, Amiga was purchased by Commodore Business Systems. The Amiga computer was originally intended to be a gaming system, but was redesigned as a personal computer and released. It was well known as having a better User Interface than the IBM-PC and less expensive than the Macintosh. ","Monday"];
Events[227]=["August","16","1890","The Census bureau releases it's first results tabulated automatically","Herman Hollerith's tabulating machine won a competition to tabulate the US Census and the first results from his invention were officially released on this date. Using punched cards, the totals were tabulated and recorded. His company was eventually merged with others and in 1924, it became what we now know as IBM.","Tuesday"];
Events[228]=["August","17","1982","The first CD is manufactured","The Phillips factory in Langenhagen Germany manufactures the first Compact Disc. After more than a quarter of a century, this medium is only just starting to decline in popularity.","Wednesday"];
Events[229]=["August","18","1947","Hewlett-Packard is incorporated","William Hewlett and David Packard built various electronic components in their garage in Palo Alto, California. One of their first big customers was Disney, who purchased some oscillators used for the Fantasia movie being produced.","Thursday"];
Events[230]=["August","19","2004","Google becomes a pubic company","After being a private company for five years, going public was a huge event giving Google a market capitalization of $23 billion dollars. ","Friday"];
Events[231]=["August","20","1970","John Carmack is born","John Carmack co-founded id Software and was the lead programmer on Wolfenstein 3D, Quake and Doom, three of the most popular early FPS (First-person shooter) games for the personal computer making heavy use of 3D rendering.","Saturday"];
Events[232]=["August","21","1888","Patent received for a Calculating Machine","The Burroughs Corporation had been in business for only a couple years by this point and this was the first in long line of business machines. Eventually, Burroughs merged with the Sperry corporation to form what is now Unisys.","Sunday"];
Events[233]=["August","22","1955","First Computer User Group formed","The group SHARE was formed for the users of the IBM Model 704 computer to exchange ideas and programs. The group was mainly scientists and engineers at the companies that used the 704. Since these computers were very expensive, this group was able to greatly influence IBM when making decisions on design and support.","Monday"];
Events[234]=["August","23","1995","Jay Leno helps launch Windows 95","During a rehearsal for the Windows 95 launch, Jay Leno quips 'I came [here] illiterate, now I'm leaving virtually retarded...'","Tuesday"];
Events[235]=["August","24","1996","Windows NT 4.0 is released","The NT line of Operating Systems were focused on business customers and were generally considered more stable than the consumer versions, such as Windows 95 and 98. This release did, however, take the User Interface from Windows 95, which was released a year earlier.","Wednesday"];
Events[236]=["August","25","1980","Microsoft announces a Unix-based operating system","This seems out of character for the company that has worked so hard to distinguish itself from Unix. Microsoft licensed the rights to Unix and contracted with SCO to migrate it to personal computers. One year later, work is begun on a new project that will be released as Windows 1.0.","Thursday"];
Events[237]=["August","26","1984","Ms Manners weighs in on computer use for the first time","Judith Martin has been writing as Ms Manners since 1978. It wasn't until 1984 that she first addressed how computer use and etiquette overlapped. On this day, she made it very clear that personal letters should always be hand-written. Failure to do so could sow seeds of discontent as it is tempting to copy and paste content in letters between friends.","Friday"];
Events[238]=["August","27","1963","The Electric Field Controlled Semiconductor Device patent is granted","This device, commonly known as a MOSFET or simply, MOS, is a building block for CMOS, which in turn is the basis for producing integrated circuits.  The idea behind the MOSFET goes back as far as 1925, but it took many years of research to come up with the working version in the late 1950s and finally a patent on this date in 1963.","Saturday"];
Events[239]=["August","28","1655","William Oughtred wrote a letter to John Evelyn","While John Evelyn was a well-known English writer, it's William Oughtred with the computer-related history. After John Napier invented logarithms , and Edmund Gunter created the logarithmic scales upon which slide rules are based, it was Oughtred who combined these to be credited as the inventor of the slide rule.","Sunday"];
Events[240]=["August","29","1990","The British Computer Misuse Act goes into effect","Prior to this, it was difficult to prosecute malicious hackers for crimes because computer crimes were not  well suited to prosecution through existing laws. The delivery of two email messages to the Duke of Edinburgh's private email by two men that had gained unauthorized access to a British Telecom computer system may have prompted this law.","Monday"];
Events[241]=["August","30","1969","node 1' of the ARPANET comes online","UCLA is host to the first computer to officially bring about the ARPANET. This network was originally used for government and military research at the time. Eventually, this will be opened up and be known as the Internet.","Tuesday"];
Events[242]=["August","31","1956","Artificial Intelligence has it's first formal discussion","While the idea of a thinking machine has been around for millennia, this discussion on Artificial Intelligence was held at Dartmouth. It is during this time that the term 'Artificial Intelligence' is coined as a study of how to formally describe procedures for learning so that a computer can understand ideas and simulate learning.","Wednesday"];
Events[243]=["September","1","1989","The first CD-ROM drive for laptops is shipped","The Grid MXV-01 CD-ROM drive by Grid systems is shipped for their series of laptop computers. This drive is the first for a battery-powered laptop.","Thursday"];
Events[244]=["September","2","2008","Google releases a test version of Chrome","Google was first incorporated ten years earlier as a search engine company. In that time, they were able to capitalize on that business and justify producing additional products, such as their Chrome web browser. ","Friday"];
Events[245]=["September","3","2002","The sale of Napster is blocked","Napster was an online service that allowed members to share music and was in operation for two years from 1999 to 2001. It was ultimately forced to shut down after various copyright infringement lawsuits were brought against them. The sale to a German firm, Bertelsmann, was blocked on this date and the company was forced to liquidate it's assets. ","Saturday"];
Events[246]=["September","4","2001","HP buys Compaq","Hewlett-Packard (HP) was formed in 1939 as an electronic components producer. HP started getting into the computer market in the 1960s and divested itself of most other activities to form Agilent in 1999.  The 2001 purchase of the computer manufacturer Compaq was in line with other purchases the company had made over the years.","Sunday"];
Events[247]=["September","5","1985","Gateway 2000 was founded","This company was one of the first companies to sell personal computers directly to consumers.  Starting out in Iowa, moving to South Dakota and eventually to California, Gateway has constantly reinvented itself to stay profitable. In 2002, they started moving into consumer electronics such as TVs and digital cameras.","Monday"];
Events[248]=["September","6","1989","Computer Bug Accuses Thousands","Instead of sending 41000 Parisians notices of various traffic violations, the letters that came from the computer system accused them of either murder, prostitution or extortion.","Tuesday"];
Events[249]=["September","7","1994","Apple announces OS licensing","Apple started to license their Macintosh operating system to hardware producers for the first time, making them an alternative to the Microsoft Windows operating system. This lated until 1997 when Steve Jobs returned to head the company.","Wednesday"];
Events[250]=["September","8","1966","First Episode of Star Trek is Aired","The series was not a big hit originally and only lasted until 1969. However, it continues to be broadcast in syndication. This was not the first television series based in science fiction, but is arguably the most popular. It has inspired a series of moves and an animated TV series as well.","Thursday"];
Events[251]=["September","9","1980","First Home Banking by Computer","First Tennessee Bank allows consumers to connect through Compuserve to do home banking. The Internet wasn't widely available, but dial-up services such as Compuserve were becoming popular.","Friday"];
Events[252]=["September","10","1947","Grace Hopper's joke","The day after the 'first bug' was found in the Mark II, Grace Hopper spread some plastic bed bugs around as a joke. Someone in the computer lab panicked when they saw the bugs and the computer was shut down for a couple days while the source of the infestation was investigated. She didn't confess to the prank until more than twenty years later.","Saturday"];
Events[253]=["September","11","1940","First Demonstration of Remote Computing","At a meeting of the American Mathematical Society in New Hampshire, Dr George Stibitz uses a telephone to send equations to be calculated and have the results sent to a 'teleprinter' installed at the meeting while being connected to a computer in New York.","Sunday"];
Events[254]=["September","12","1958","Jack Kilby records his ideas for an 'integrated circuit'","Integrated circuits are miniaturized electronic circuits used in producing electronic equipment and computers. Both Jack Kilby and Robert Noyce are given credit for being the founder of 'integrated circuits', though each came up with idea independently. It was on this day that Jack Kilby first records his ideas for the 'integrated circuit'","Monday"];
Events[255]=["September","13","1985","Super Mario Brothers is Released","This release was for the Japanese market. When being prepared for the American market, Nintendo was being hounded for back rent by a landlord named Mario Seagle. After a very heated exchange to convince him that he would be paid, the project team decided to name the main character after their landlord.","Tuesday"];
Events[256]=["September","14","1999","Handspring Visor is Launched","After the creators of the Palm Pilot became unhappy with the direction that 3Com was taking the product line, they formed a new company called Handspring. This line had several unique features, USB synchronization (instead of the slower Serial connection) and an expansion port.","Wednesday"];
Events[257]=["September","15","1987","X11 is released","The X Windows system is a standardized graphical user interface for the Unix Operating System. In the early 1980s, before Windows and the Macintosh were available and after the Apple Lisa, the Unix world had X Windows. It wasn't until this date in 1987 that the current X11 standard was released. ","Thursday"];
Events[258]=["September","16","1997","Steve Jobs is re-instated as CEO","After being pushed out years earlier and starting the NeXT company, he is asked back to be CEO of Apple.","Friday"];
Events[259]=["September","17","1991","Linux kernel 0.01 is introduced","The GNU foundation was started in 1983 with the goal of providing a completely free and open source version of Unix and it's utilities. By 1991, many of the utilities had been developed, but they all required an operating system to run on. On this day in 1991, Linus Torvalds introduced the world to his first version of the Linux kernel to fill this need. ","Saturday"];
Events[260]=["September","18","1995","Netscape Navigator 2.0 is released","This early internet browser was known for the support of Java applets. The Java Applet added more application-like features to web pages and existed prior to other technologies such as Adobe's Flash and Microsoft's Slverlight.","Sunday"];
Events[261]=["September","19","1919","A Paper describing a 'flip-flop' circuit is published","Frank Wilfred Jordan and William Henry Eccles had invented the 'flip-flop' circuit the year before and a paper that describes it was published on this day in 1919. The 'flip-flop' circuit is the basis for the circuit used to store information in computer memory.","Monday"];
Events[262]=["September","20","1954","The First Fortran program is run","FORTRAN stands for FORmula TRANSlation. This programming language was one of the very first human-readable languages used for writing programs. Without this or similar computer languages, programmers needed to enter in the more cryptic machine codes.","Tuesday"];
Events[263]=["September","21","1983","The FCC Approves it's First Cellphone","Mobile phones had existed prior to this, but they required an operator and were either installed in a vehicle or needed a bag to contain all the equipment. This phone weighing in at 28 oz (6-7 times heavier than current cellphones) was revolutionary for it's time.","Wednesday"];
Events[264]=["September","22","1983","Arrests made in ARPANET breach","The ARPANET was a military computer network that eventually became the basis for the Internet. On this day, Ron Austin and Kevin Poulsen were arrested for gaining unauthorized access to this network. These two were also charged with multiple counts of wire fraud when they were able to manipulate phone contests and win large prizes.","Thursday"];
Events[265]=["September","23","1983","The GNU Free Software Foundation is Announced","Richard Stallman was unhappy with the claims of copyright for Unix, especially since it contained code contributed by users, without compensation. This foundation would promote a free and open source version of unix and it's utilities. This ultimately led to the production of Linux and many other popular software products.","Friday"];
Events[266]=["September","24","1979","CompuServe comes online","Before the ARPANET was opened up as the Internet, services such as CompuServe were becoming popular. Modems would allow multiple users use their telephone to dial into a computer and get access to discussion groups, information and email.","Saturday"];
Events[267]=["September","25","1928","The Company That Will Become Motorola is founded","The Galvin Manufacturing Corporation is founded on this date. Within two years, the Motorola brand would be used for the company's first car radio. In 1947, the company would change it's name to Motorola.","Sunday"];
Events[268]=["September","26","2007","eBay Users' Data is Exposed","About 1200 eBay users had their data posted on the 'Trust and Safety' forum by an unknown hacker. These breaches are not uncommon and plans are now in place to recover more quickly.","Monday"];
Events[269]=["September","27","1998","Google's Birthday","This date falls somewhere between the beginning of the company and the launch of the search engine. Google uses this date to celebrate its birthday.","Tuesday"];
Events[270]=["September","28","1925","Seymour Cray is born","Cray was intent on building the world's fastest computers and was successful for many decades. His training was in electrical engineering and had worked more than ten years in the industry before striking out on his own to create his own research lab.","Wednesday"];
Events[271]=["September","29","1954","CERN is established","Known recently for the Large Hadron Collider, it was started as an international research facility for high-energy physics. It also is the birthplace of the World Wide Web, which was developed as a system for sharing content between scientists.","Thursday"];
Events[272]=["September","30","1980","Parts of the Ethernet specifications are announced","Ethernet is a wiring and signaling standard that is part of the OSI model for computer networking and serves as the de facto standard for personal computers as well as server-grade computers.","Friday"];
Events[273]=["October","1","1962","J.C.R. Licklider is appointed to IPTO","After working on the SAGE system, he was appointed to the Pentagon's Information Processing Techniques Office (IPTO). It was in this position that he funded many projects, such as the one headed by Douglas Englebart which culminated in the 'Mother of All Demos' as well as the seeds for the ARPANET.","Saturday"];
Events[274]=["October","2","1955","The ENIAC is Turned Off","After it's first use nine years earlier, on this date, it is turned off and dismantled. Today, pieces of that computer are in various museums around the United States.","Sunday"];
Events[275]=["October","3","1996","Red Hat Linux v4.0 is released","Red Hat was one of the first successes in a company making money on Linux. In this release, the Sparc processor was first supported.","Monday"];
Events[276]=["October","4","1968","Personal Computer is used for the first time in an ad","The Hewlett-Packard 911A was a programmable desktop calculator. The term 'Personal Computer' is used for the first time for an actual product in an ad in Science magazine. ","Tuesday"];
Events[277]=["October","5","1996","Seymour Cray dies in an auto accident","Although he worked tirelessly to push the limits of computer performance, he resisted parallel processing where many less powerful processors could be used instead of a single high-power processor. He is credited with saying, 'If you were plowing a field, which would you rather use: Two strong oxen or 1024 chickens?'","Wednesday"];
Events[278]=["October","6","1987","Excel is Unveiled","Excel was not the first computer spreadsheet application, but it is the best known. At the time it was released, it was not bundled with other applications as it it today. This version was also the first major application for the Windows 2.0 Operating System.","Thursday"];
Events[279]=["October","7","1968","The first conference to discuss 'Software Engineering' is held","NATO's Science Committee had been discussing the pending 'Software Crisis' and how it affected it's member nations. The crisis was the lack of formal methods to produce software and the term 'Software Engineering' was coined as a provocative conceptualization of what a solution could be.","Friday"];
Events[280]=["October","8","1997","Yahoo! acquires Four11","Yahoo! started out as a directory of web sites, Their search engine and free email hosting came later. This purchase of Four11 gave them access to Rocketmail, an existing free email hosting service that they offered to the public at no charge.","Saturday"];
Events[281]=["October","9","1922","A Robot Appears on Broadway for the first time","While the idea of mechanical men had been around for quite some time, the term 'robot' was coined in a play, R.U.R. (Rossum's Universal Robots) and opens on broadway. It was written by Czech playwright Karel Capek in 1921","Sunday"];
Events[282]=["October","10","1981","Donkey Kong Arcade Version is Released","This is one of the first and best arcade games. High scores are being sought and broken even as late as 2007. There has even been a documentary made called 'The King of Kong: A Fistfull of Quarters'.","Monday"];
Events[283]=["October","11","1994","IBM Announces OS/2 Warp","Within the month of the announcement, this version of OS/2 is released. It is a year before Windows 95 will be released. Originally a joint effort between Microsoft and IBM, Microsoft abandoned it in favor of their own Windows line. One major feature was it's support of Internet connectivity.","Tuesday"];
Events[284]=["October","12","1931","Ole-Johan Dahl is born","Dahl, a Norwegian Computer Scientist, developed the ideas for object-oriented programming in the 1960s.  These ideas will take decades to achieve general acceptance by software engineers.","Wednesday"];
Events[285]=["October","13","1994","Microsoft Announces Plans to Buy Intuit","This was not to be and was eventually cancelled. The deal was valued at about $1.5 Billion.","Thursday"];
Events[286]=["October","14","1985","The First Commercial Version of C++ is Released","Nearly twelve years before an international standard is agreed upon, C++ has been made available commercially. The original compiler was called cfront and provided the de facto standard for the language until the international standard was approved in 1997.","Friday"];
Events[287]=["October","15","1990","Apple's Mac Classic is Unveiled","Breaking the $1000 price point for the first time for a Macintosh, users were more likely to consider this line of Macintosh than before. While many people liked to use them, the price typically kept many consumers away.","Saturday"];
Events[288]=["October","16","1956","FORTRAN is Released","The first program was run two years earlier and it took time to ensure it was ready for public use. IBM, led by John Backus, developed a the system starting in 1954 that eventually led to FORTRAN.","Sunday"];
Events[289]=["October","17","2001","The First Generation iPod is launched","Apple came late to the portable music market, but with the iTunes application released earlier in the year, the platform was complete to establish a mechanism to manage the content of the iPod. The iTunes Store won't be released for another 18 months.","Monday"];
Events[290]=["October","18","1995","Mortal Kombat 3 for PC is released","This game used new techniques to increase the realism and gore. Actors were filmed and frame-by-frame, were added to the game.  ","Tuesday"];
Events[291]=["October","19","1987","Computerized Trading Programs cause the Dow Jones Industrial Average to drop 22.6%","Often referred to as 'Black Monday' a variety of events including SEC investigations triggered some computerized trading programs to sell stocks, this in turn triggered other programs and soon many of the systems involved crashed under the load.","Wednesday"];
Events[292]=["October","20","1999","Encyclopedia Britannica Launches a Free Online Version","It immediately crashes with the traffic. Of the ten million people that tried to get access, only a hundred thousand actually got through. ","Thursday"];
Events[293]=["October","21","2005","Doom, the movie, is released","It made roughly $42 million in ticket sales. The bad news was that it cost $100 million to make.","Friday"];
Events[294]=["October","22","2009","Microsoft opens it's first storefront","Various computer manufacturers have tried to create storefronts with mixed success. On this date in 2009, Microsoft tries it's hand at retail.","Saturday"];
Events[295]=["October","23","1972","The first Teletext service is announced","The BBC announces plans to send information services through the television signal which can be viewed with a decoder connected to the television or as part of the television itself. While the service won't be available for another two years, it has maintained it's relevance to the current time. ","Sunday"];
Events[296]=["October","24","1959","Mooer's Law is Proposed","Not to be confused with 'Moore's Law', Mooer's Law states 'An information retrieval system will tend not to be used whenever it is more painful and troublesome for a customer to have information than for him not to have it.'","Monday"];
Events[297]=["October","25","1922","The Mechanical Man' was released in Italy","Released six years before the famous 'Metropolis' film, this was one of the earliest films to feature a robot in the story. However, the term 'Robot' was only recently coined and not associated with these mechanical men stories.","Tuesday"];
Events[298]=["October","26","1960","The first computer-generated script is aired","A program called Sage II was written at MIT to generate short scripts where characters are choreographed. A few of these short scripts were aired on CBS in honor of MIT's 100th anniversary.","Wednesday"];
Events[299]=["October","27","1992","Microsoft Windows for Workgroups 3.1 is shipped","Two years before OS/2 Warp, which featured built-in internet connectivity, Microsoft ships Windows for Workgroups. This is geared towards businesses where connected computers are more of a necessity.","Thursday"];
Events[300]=["October","28","1985","Microsoft announces IPO","After ten years of being a privately-held company, Bill Gates decides to make Microsoft a public company. In 1986 when the IPO takes, place, it effectively sets the value of Microsoft to be over half a billion dollars.","Friday"];
Events[301]=["October","29","1969","First Successful Message Sent Over ARPANET","The ARPANET was a US-government funded project to connect computers in different locations by a network. Decades later, this will be made public and be called the Internet. This message was actually a second attempt at sending a message, the first attempt crashed the computer.","Saturday"];
Events[302]=["October","30","1996","Enlightenment is Released","X Windows is the most common Graphical User Interface standard used on Unix (and Linux) computers and had been around for nearly fifteen years by this point. The Enlightenment project was an add-on to X Windows that made applications more easily accessible and provided for a better user experience.","Sunday"];
Events[303]=["October","31","1988","OS/2 is Announced","A joint venture between IBM and Microsoft for a new Graphical User Interface has resulted in OS/2. By this time. Microsoft is already working on their own line of Windows, which will eventually become the leader for personal computer Operating Systems.","Monday"];
Events[304]=["November","1","1983","The IBM PCjr is Announced","The computers themselves were not to be shipped until the spring of 1984 and this announcement was intended to create demand prior to the release. The PCjr was intended for home and educational use by being less expensive than the business-oriented IBM PC and similar in functionality to the Commodore 64 and Apple II series. ","Tuesday"];
Events[305]=["November","2","1988","The First Large-Scale Internet Worm Appears","A worm is a program that replicates itself on multiple computers over a network. While the first network-based worms existed as early as the first networks, the Morris Worm, is the first internet-based worm to spread widely.","Wednesday"];
Events[306]=["November","3","1994","Red Hat Linux v1.0 was released","Red Hat Linux was developed independently before being purchased to create Red Hat Software. When this company went public in 1999, it was very well received. The irony is that this company specializes in giving away software and selling the servicing of that software as well as some of the utilities created for Red Hat Linux.","Thursday"];
Events[307]=["November","4","1952","UNIVAC I Predicts the Election of Eisenhower","In August of that year, CBS's Walter Cronkite and others visited an installation of the UNIVAC I to see if claims made by Remington-Rand PR that the computer could predict the election. That trip convinced them that it would be possible. The program ultimately written was able to predict the outcome to within about 3% of the popular vote.","Friday"];
Events[308]=["November","5","1988","Cornell Student Confirmed as Worm Author","The large-scale internet worm that struck three days earlier was traced back to Cornell University student Robert Morris Jr. Since this was determined to be a malicious attack, he was kicked out of school, given probation and a large fine.","Saturday"];
Events[309]=["November","6","1980","IBM contracts with Microsoft to Create MS-DOS","Less than six months before the release of the IBM PC, Microsoft is contacted build MS-DOS. Microsoft was only about five years old at the time and was considered a small company. The success of MS-DOS helped Microsoft, who retained the rights to the Operating System, become a major player in the new personal computer software industry.","Sunday"];
Events[310]=["November","7","1994","WXYC Announces Their Plans to Broadcast on the Internet","While Internet radio had existed prior to this. WXYC out of Chapel Hill, North Carolina, was the first traditional radio station to make such an announcement.","Monday"];
Events[311]=["November","8","1991","WordPerfect for Windows is Released","During the 1980s, WordPerfect was the primary system used for generating documents on a computer. Not only did WordPerfect work on IBM-compatible Personal Computers, but it was also available for Unix, Apple II, and many others. By the end of the 1990s, it fell in popularity to Microsoft Word. ","Tuesday"];
Events[312]=["November","9","2004","Firefox Web Browser v1.0 is released","Some of the developers working on the Mozilla Web Browser felt that it was becoming too 'bloated' and that a more streamlined version needed to be built. An experimental branch of Mozilla was created and the first version of that branch, now called Firefox, was released. Today, Firefox is the second most popular web browser in use today.","Wednesday"];
Events[313]=["November","10","1983","Microsoft Windows is Announced","While it won't be released for two more years, Microsoft boldly predicts that 90% of all PCs will use this system by the end of 1984.","Thursday"];
Events[314]=["November","11","1994","Mosaic Communications to Become Netscape Communications Corp.","On this day, Jim Clark announces that his company will soon use the name Netscape Communications Corporation. He started the company Silicon Graphics that made specialized computers for rendering graphics. The name change is inevitable to reduce confusion about the ownership of the code.","Friday"];
Events[315]=["November","12","1989","Tim Berners-Lee Formally Proposes a Research Project That Will Produce the World Wide Web","The idea of hypertext, where clicking on a link will take you to a new document, had been around for decades. In the early 1980s, Berners-Lee had prototyped a simple hypertext system, but it was incomplete. On this date, a formal proposal is made to management at the CERN lab to produce this system. ","Saturday"];
Events[316]=["November","13","1989","The First Web Page is Written","In support of his new proposal titled 'World Wide Web: Proposal for a Hypertext Project', Tim Berners-Lee writes a simple web page to demonstrate the idea.","Sunday"];
Events[317]=["November","14","1997","C++ draft standard is submitted for approval","Both the ANSI (American National Standards Institute) and ISO (International Standards Organization) have committees working on the formal standards for the C++ programming language. This programming language will provide object-oriented programming capabilities.","Monday"];
Events[318]=["November","15","1971","The Intel 4004 Microprocessor is Released","This was the first Central Processing Unit (CPU) to be produced on a single chip. Before this chip, it took several chips to have a 'complete' CPU. By adding in a RAM (Random Access Memory) or ROM (Read-Only Memory) chips, a fully programmable computer could be built.","Tuesday"];
Events[319]=["November","16","1992","Microsoft Access 1.0 is Shipped","For decades, databases were the sole realm of large systems. The previous decade saw several PC-based database systems producer. Access has since become a very popular platform to combine reports, data storage and computer programming in an accessible way to users that do not have a strong programming background.","Wednesday"];
Events[320]=["November","17","1951","J Lyons Runs the First Business Application on a Computer","J Lyons, a United Kingdom food company took an early interest in computers for business use. On this date, they ran the first business application on a computer. They went on to create the LEO Computer company to sell and service computers for corporations.","Thursday"];
Events[321]=["November","18","1996","Intel CEO predicts 10Ghz processors by 2011","Predicting processor speed for fifteen years in the future is difficult to do. As of 2010, it seems that he will be short, but not by much.","Friday"];
Events[322]=["November","19","1955","Parkinson's Law Appears for the First Time in Print","Parkinson's Law states that 'Work expands to fill the time for it's completion'. This has often been used to promote aggressive schedules for producing software.","Saturday"];
Events[323]=["November","20","1963","Hackers is First Used in Reference to Computing","Hacking has been a term used for hundreds of years, however this term appears for the first time in print in relation to computers in the MIT student newspaper, 'Many telephone services have been curtailed because of so-called hackers,  the majority of the MIT phones are 'trapped.'' ","Sunday"];
Events[324]=["November","21","1969","The First ARPANET Link is Made","The ARPANET was a government-funded networking project to produce a reliable an standardized method for connecting computers of different Operating Systems.  Eventually, this will become the basis for the Internet.","Monday"];
Events[325]=["November","22","1995","Toy Story is Released","Toy Story has the distinction of being the first feature-length movie to have the video portion completely computer generated.","Tuesday"];
Events[326]=["November","23","2007","A MA15+ Rating is Given to 'Soldier of Fortune:Payback' in Australia","This computer game rating went beyond the normal 'recommendation' for anyone under 15, it carried the weight of legal authority to require that anyone under 15 wanting to purchase or rent this game must be accompanied by a parent or legal guardian. The game was withdrawn and not sold in Australia.","Wednesday"];
Events[327]=["November","24","1999","iMesh was released","While not the first filesharing system, it was one of the first popular ones for internet users. It allowed a file to be downloaded from one of many known good copies across the userbase. They are also notable for being sued by the RIAA (Recording Industry Association of America) for promoting piracy.","Thursday"];
Events[328]=["November","25","2002","Roxio Acquires the Napster Brand and Assets","Napster was a song-sharing service that was sued for promoting illegal file sharing of copyrighted song files. After a several year fight, the company was forced to close down. Roxio resurrects the brand and logo and runs a legal online music service.","Friday"];
Events[329]=["November","26","1976","Microsoft is Incorporated","Even though the software giant is now located in Washington state, it's roots are in New Mexico. Within three years, they will move to Redmond.","Saturday"];
Events[330]=["November","27","2000","Space Shuttle Simulator 'Orbiter' is released","This freeware software for Microsoft Windows was popular not for the graphics, but for the realism of the controls. It continues to be available today with a large following of users and contributors.","Sunday"];
Events[331]=["November","28","1995","Internet Explorer 2.0 is Released","Somewhat late to the web browser market, this version supports SSL, background audio and supports twelve languages.","Monday"];
Events[332]=["November","29","1972","Pong is Set Up in a Tavern","Nolan Bushnell and Al Alcorn set up this coin-operated device in Andy Capp's Tavern. The success of this machine prompted the two to found Atari for producing similar games.","Tuesday"];
Events[333]=["November","30","2006","Windows Vista is Released","With much fanfare, Windows Vista is released to corporate clients. Enhanced security and improved user interface design are touted as primary benefits. However, incompatibility for some existing systems and the drastic change in default security settings put off any wide-scale adoption. ","Wednesday"];
Events[334]=["December","1","1941","Federico Faggin is Born","Dr. Faggin is credited for being the co-inventor of the microprocessor. He provided a large portion of both the design and theory for the Intel 4004 chip.  Born in Italy, he graduated from the University of Padua in 1965. He eventually founded Zilog to produce chips for the new personal computer market.","Thursday"];
Events[335]=["December","2","1954","IBM Delivers NORC to the Navy","The Naval Ordnance Research Calculator was built by IBM and was delivered to the Naval Surface Weapons Center in Virginia. During the inauguration ceremony, it calculated pi to 3096 digits in 13 minutes, a record for the time. It provided service for many computing-intensive applications such as ballistics.","Friday"];
Events[336]=["December","3","1924","John Backus is Born","Backus is credited with leading the team that produced FORTRAN, one of the first human-readable computer languages. He also is credited with the BNF (Backus-Naur Form, or Backus Normal Form). The BNF is a formal way to describe a computer language in a way that is not ambiguous and promotes mathematical analysis.","Saturday"];
Events[337]=["December","4","1987","OS/2 is Released","Two years after Windows 1.0 and a month after Windows 2.0, the once joint venture with Microsoft sees it's first version released. IBM has since ceased support, but the product lives on through a company called eComStation.","Sunday"];
Events[338]=["December","5","1941","The Z3 Computer is Completed","Konrad Zuse, a German Engineer,  completes his digital computer, the first digital computer to be run by a program. Within five years, he will publish the details of the first high-level programming language, Plankalkul.","Monday"];
Events[339]=["December","6","1941","The Company to be Known as Texas Instruments is Purchased","Geophysical Service Incorporated (GSI) was formed in the early 1930s to provide petroleum search services. On this date in 1941, four investors purchased the company, just one day before the U.S. entered into WW II. By 1951, the company changed it's name to Texas Instruments and later sold off the GSI division to focus exclusively on electronics.","Tuesday"];
Events[340]=["December","7","1972","Rolling Stone Announces The First Computer Game Championship","In an article titled 'S P A C E W A R - Fanatic Life and Symbolic Death Among the Computer Bums', Rolling Stone announces an upcoming 'Intergalactic spacewar olympics' where players compete in a game of 'Spacewar' on a PDP-10. The game was created more than ten years earlier and has somewhat the same feel as 'Asteroids'. ","Wednesday"];
Events[341]=["December","8","1943","The Colossus is Delivered to Bletchley Park","Blechley Park was Britain's main cryptanalysis facility during World War II. This system used vacuum tubes to perform calculations and read data from paper tape, much like punched cards, but in a continuous strip.","Thursday"];
Events[342]=["December","9","1968","The Mother of All Demos' is Held","Douglas Englebart has taken his inspiration from Vanevar Bush's 'As We May Think' and has produced a custom network of computers. This demo shows many great ideas including, audio/video conferencing, the first public use of the computer mouse, ergonomic office furniture built with computers in mind and much more.","Friday"];
Events[343]=["December","10","1993","Doom for MS-DOS is released","This first version was 'shareware' where users were encouraged to share it and pay for it if they liked it. This was one of the first popularized 3D games.","Saturday"];
Events[344]=["December","11","1984","SyQuest Receives US Patent","Patent 4488187 was for a Servo Control Apparatus, which was featured prominently in their early removable drives. ","Sunday"];
Events[345]=["December","12","1980","Apple Computer Goes Public","Until this point, Apple was a private company. After the sale, the company was worth $10 million US.  Coincidentally, US Copyright Law is extended to software for the first time on this date as well.","Monday"];
Events[346]=["December","13","2004","David Wheeler Dies","Professor Wheeler worked on EDSAC, an early computer and wrote the first stored program. He was involved with establishing the notion of a subroutine, a set of steps that were separate from other parts of the code and could be used repeatedly. He also worked on data compression techniques.","Tuesday"];
Events[347]=["December","14","1989","ANSI-C is Approved","Originally developed more than fifteen years earlier, the C computer language is now standardized by ANSI (American National Standards Institute). With this standard in place, code written in ANSI-C can be used on a variety of platforms that support this standard.","Wednesday"];
Events[348]=["December","15","1999","Windows 2000 is Released","Computer manufacturers are the first to get this new operating system from Microsoft. Previous versions of Windows were fundamentally different for desktop and server systems. This is the first version of Windows to consolidate the underlying technology between desktops and servers.","Thursday"];
Events[349]=["December","16","2006","Scheme R6RS Feedback is Published","Scheme is a variant of the computer language Lisp. Lisp started development in 1956 and Scheme started development in 1975. The two languages have diverged somewhat, though can look similar. ","Friday"];
Events[350]=["December","17","1996","The 'Option Red' Supercomputer is Started Up","This computer is set up at the Sandia National Laboratory and can perform one trillion floating-point operations a second It was built with more than 9000 Intel Processors, 600Gb Ram and 2 Tb (2000GB) of hard drive space. It is the fastest computer of it's time.","Saturday"];
Events[351]=["December","18","1987","Perl is Released","Originally developed as a scripting language to generate reports, Perl has been expanded to be a general purpose computer language. In practice, the language can be difficult to read due to it's ability to be terse. This has lead to Perl being described as 'Making simple things difficult and difficult things possible'","Sunday"];
Events[352]=["December","19","1921","Adin Falkoff is Born","Adin Falkoff is born in New Jersey and goes on to receive his degree in Chemical Engineering and then on to earn his Master's in Mathematics from Yale. He is one of the co-inventors of APL 'A Programming Language'. It heavily used symbols instead of words and was difficult to read without some basic instruction.","Monday"];
Events[353]=["December","20","1943","Norman Bel Geddes is Chosen to Design the Case for the Mark I","This controversial announcement was not a comment on Bel Geddes' abilities, but the timing and expense. The case would cost $100,000 and many thought this extravagance could not be afforded during a time of war (WW II). Norman Bel Geddes also designed General Motor's Pavilion for the 1939 Worlds Fair.","Tuesday"];
Events[354]=["December","21","1999","The Quake Engine Source Code is Released Under the GNU license","After id Software's successful products Doom and Quake, the company released the core engine for Quake to be modified and used freely for non-commercial use.","Wednesday"];
Events[355]=["December","22","1972","RFC 433 is Proposed","The RFC (Request For Comment) system was initially an informal way to discuss proposed features and standards for the ARPANET. In RFC 433, the idea that certain system applications should use standard socket is documented. For example, Telnet would be socket 1, FTP would be socket 3, etc. ","Thursday"];
Events[356]=["December","23","1947","The Transistor is First Demonstrated to a Small Audience","There are several claims to who invented the transistor. AT&T Bell Telephone Labs presents their findings to a small group. This idea will be improved upon and be heavily used to improve the performance and reduce the power consumption of future computers.","Friday"];
Events[357]=["December","24","1904","Joseph Juran is Born","He is credited with generalizing the '80/20 rule' in 1937. The rule is generalized as '80% of the effects are from 20% of the causes'.  Twenty years earlier, a man named Pareto noticed that 80 percent of the land was owned by 20 percent of the population in Italy. Pareto also developed the 'Pareto Charts' as part of his work as an economist.","Saturday"];
Events[358]=["December","25","1990","The First WWW Server is Online","During a Christmas break, Tim Berners-Lee completes the first Web Browser, Web Server and WYSIWYG HTML Editor. He turns on his server to produce the first WWW server on the Internet.","Sunday"];
Events[359]=["December","26","1982","TIME's Man of the Year is Not a Person","The Computer gets the honor of being the most influential during the year. This is the first object to receive the honor. Within ten years, the Earth will become the second.","Monday"];
Events[360]=["December","27","1962","First Patent Filed For a Removable Disk","While it will be nearly twenty years before a practical consumer version will be developed, the first patent is filed on this date.  The machine described in the patent application is roughly the size of a dishwasher, with a clear lid with a hard drive platter on top.","Tuesday"];
Events[361]=["December","28","1903","John von Neumann is Born","Von Neumann was an influential leader in several fields.He is best know for his description of the 'Von Neumann' style computer where both data and program instructions are in the same memory where a control unit would interact with the memory and the Arithmetic/Logic Unit as well as various input/output channels to perform it's calculations.","Wednesday"];
Events[362]=["December","29","1998","New York Times Article Appears on 'Les Horribles Cernettes'","This group of CERN women have written songs and performed at various events. They hold the distinction of the first band to have a web site and the first image on the web is of the band.","Thursday"];
Events[363]=["December","30","1967","Joint Resolution 1180-420 is Issued between the Communist Party and the USSR Council of Ministers","This resolution assigned the USSR Radio Industry Ministry the responsibility for the Ryad series of computers.  Throughout it's history, they have promoted the use of supercomputing capabilities across the former Soviet Union and now Russia as well as educational use of computers.","Friday"];
Events[364]=["December","31","1974","The Altair 8800 Appears in Popular Electronics","Not only was this considered the first 'personal computer', it was also the platform for one of Microsoft's first implementations of Basic. At this time, Microsoft has not even been incorporated, but will soon be.","Saturday"];


var months = new Array("January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December");
var currenttime = new Date();
var month = currenttime.getMonth();
var day = currenttime.getDate();
var i = 0;

for (i = 0; i<365;i++)
{
  if ((Events[i][0] == months[month]) && (Events[i][1]== day)) { break;}
}

document.write('<div align="center">');
document.write(Events[i][0]+' '+Events[i][1]+', '+Events[i][2]+'<br/>');
document.write('<b>'+Events[i][3]+'</b>');
document.write('</div>');
document.write(Events[i][4]);

</script>

]]>
</Content>
</Module>
